# Darshan Washimkar

1221 University Ave #E302 Fort Collins, CO 80521 | Phone: (970)-232-0660 | Email:darshan.wash@gmail.com

Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/darshanwashimkar | Website: http://darshanwashimkar.github.io

#### PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

Highly motivated computer science graduate student with a strong knowledge of **Computer Networking**, , **Distributed Systems**, **Big Data Analysis** and **Bioinformatics**. Accomplished a couple of **research projects** and also have more than **30 months experience** in the software industry.

## **TECHNICAL EXPERTISE** [N – Novice, I – Intermediate, P – Professional]

Languages: C [P] C++ [P] Java [P] Python [P]

Data Analytics: Hadoop [N] MapReduce [N] SQL [I]

Networking Protocols: TCP [P] IPv4 [P] IPv6 [P] BGP [P] Chord [P] Web Technologies: HTML5 [P] JavaScript [P] jQuery [P] KML [I] PHP [I]

Databases/Tools: Oracle [I] MySQL [I] Network Simulator [I] Eclipse [P] VMware[P]

Cloud Services: Amazon Web Services (AWS) [N]

#### **EDUCATION**

Master of Science, Computer Science Aug 2016 (Expected)

Colorado State University, Fort Collins, CO, USA GPA: 3.85/4

**Bachelor of Technology, Information Technology** 

Shri Guru Gobind Singhji Institute of Engineering and Technology, Nanded, MH, India GPA: 7.8/10

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### Graduate Teaching Assistant, Colorado State University

Jan 2015 - Dec 2015

May 2011

- In fall 2015, I taught (CS356) Computer Security and (CS457) Computer Networks and the Internet
- In spring 2015, I taught (CS557) Advanced Computer Networking and (CS160) Foundations in Programming
- Conduct two recitations every week and teach ~30 students
- Also, responsible for grading, creating assignments, solving assignment related queries and serving as a lab manager

#### Programmer Analyst, Cognizant Technology Solution, Pune, India

June 2011 - Sept 2013

- Programmed websites, mobile applications and e-mailers using JavaScript, ¡Query, HTML 5, XML, JAVA, ASP.net
- Gathered and analyzed requirements for the world's top pharmaceutical firms
- Maintained websites, fixed existing bugs and improved websites loading time
- Awards
  - > Awarded for innovative "honey bee" gaming application. It was a POC, demonstrating our capabilities [team of 2]
  - > Member of 6 person team which was awarded "Low Cost Solutions Project Of The Year" for highest efficiency

#### **ACADEMIC PROJECTS**

Optimal Selection of Enzyme Triad for Index Alignment of Contigs to Optical Maps Using MapReduce [Team size: 2] Oct 2014 – Dec 2014

- Proposed a new method to find best restriction enzyme triad from ~11 million combinations using MapReduce
- Implemented the algorithm in hadoop using python to distribute the task of finding shared sub strings in suffix tree
- Updated Dell Zhang's generalize suffix tree implementation to support Unicode characters of large range

## Forecast Use Of A City Bikeshare System [Team size: 1]

Nov 2014 - Dec 2014

- Implemented linear (LLS) and non-linear models(Neural Networks) to predict the demand for bike sharing system
- Code implementation was in **python** and the results were submitted to kaggle for competition
- Showed that non-linear model performs much better for this problem

## **♣ Cloud based Source-aware key- value store** [Team size: 1]

Oct 2014 - Dec 2014

- Distributed Hash Table (DHT) implemented from Chord paper using Java
- Used cloud computing environments like Amazon Web Services (EC2,EBS) for development

#### Genome Assembler [Team size: 1]

Aug 2014 – Dec 2014

- Implemented a sparse de Bruijn graph for genome assembly from scratch in C++
- Performed in depth theoretical investigations into various succinct data structures for de Bruijn graph optimization

#### **♣ A P2P File Sharing Network** [Team size: 1]

Feb 2014 - Mar 2014

- Project involved development of peer to peer file sharing network that uses protocol resembling BitTorrent
- Implementation of socket programming, fork, event loops was in C language

# **A File Sharing Protocol Over Named Data Networks (NDN)** [Team size: 1]

Mar 2014 - Apr 2014

- Project was implemented using CCNx library from ccnx.org in C
- Compared performance of the protocol in IP vs NDN configuration and found that NDN gave much better performance

## Low Cost Supercomputer with Cluster Computing [Team size: 3]

Aug 2010 - Apr 2011

- Built a simple-to-manage and easy to deploy HPC cluster from outdated PCs of college laboratory
- It was used to execute compute intensive software applications in an academic setting
- Used HPLinpack to evaluate performance

#### OTHER OCCUPATIONS

#### Student Scientist, Colorado State University, Fort Collins, CO

Jan 2014 - Jan 2015

- Worked on BGP Monitoring System (BGPmon) and delivered a translator module which is capable of converting Multi-Threaded Routing Toolkit (MRT) files to XML format supported by **BGPmon**
- Developed visualization tools using KML to simulate DDoS attack events like NTP reflection attack
- Found and fixed ~25 critical bugs, including improvements and built a project website. Primarily worked with C, C++

## **CERTIFICATIONS**

• Exam 70-480: Programming in HTML5 with JavaScript and CSS3 [Microsoft]

#### OTHER ACTIVITIES

- As an undergraduate, conducted a day long workshop on 'Linux Administrator And Advance Shell Scripting'
  with 60+ participants
- I was a member of Outreach and Team Everest, two groups in Cognizant that work for the cause of child literacy in rural areas.
- Organized cultural events at college level and also at 'PRAGYAA', national level technical festival in SGGS